动作快，4小时后的班机 等叫到车可能都塞车了
Hurry up! The flight leaves in four hours!There could be traffic!
飞机可能会提早起飞 在伦敦入境时可能会大排长龙，快点
The plane could leave early!In London,there could be a line at customs! Come on!
6小时的飞机，够她念了
Six-hour trip to London. That's a lot of Monica.
那是什么？ 保险套啊老兄
What have you got there?Condoms,dude.
为什么印西班牙文？
Well,how come the writing is in spanish?
别看我的套子
Don't read my condoms.
护照打勾，相机打勾 旅行支票打勾
Passport,check. Camera,check. Traveler's checks,check.
你在叫谁打勾？ 我自己
-Who are you saying "check" to? -Myself.
记得一样打一个勾 做一件好事就有个勾勾
For remembering to pack a thing.You do a good thing,you get a "check."
这是妈的习惯，我没想过很怪
Mom does it. I never realized it was weird.
我妈都把头塞进烤箱里
My mom used to put her head in the oven.
其实只有一次，不过蛮怪的
Actually,only the one time. But it's pretty weird.
准备好了吗？
Are you ready yet?
好了，机票带了吗？ 在这里，打勾
-Got the tickets? -Right here. Check!
去伦敦啰，宝贝，走吧
It's all London,baby!Here we go
护照呢？
Got your passport?
梳妆台第三个抽屉 弄丢就糟了
Third drawer of my dresser. You don't want to lose that!
快去
There it is!
本集播出：“罗斯的婚礼”
The One With Ross' Wedding
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
吸尘器在我的柜子里的左边
The vacuum's in my closet on the left side.
垃圾袋在冰箱旁边
Garbage bags are next to the refrigerator.
瑞秋会在，我不能问她吗？
Rachel's gonna be here. Can't I just ask her?
好啊，你问啊
Yeah,okay. Give that a try!
走啰 好耶
-Let's do it. -Cheerio!
伦敦，宝贝
London,baby!
我绝对不会觉得烦 伦敦，宝贝
That's not gonna get annoying.London,baby!
你知道吗？我错了
You know what? I was wrong.
人都到了，我们走吧
We're all here. Let's get going!
我很想过去抱你恭喜你 但是我起不来
I want to go over and hug you...and wish you luck,but I can't get up.
那我过去抱你 太好了，帮我拿报纸
-I'll come hug you. -Great,can you bring me the paper?
快快乐乐的结婚吧 谢谢
-Have a great wedding. -Thanks.
钱德，我也想抱你
Chandler,I want to hug you too!
顺便去你家餐台把我的书拿来
You might as well bring my book from your apartment.
我们要走了
-So we're off.
玩得开心点
-Have fun!
你居然不能去
-I can't believe you won't be there.
是啊
-I know.
去嘛，你为什么不能去？ 罗斯
Come. Why don't you come?
去嘛，一起去，我会很高兴
To London. Please? It would mean so much to me.
我要忙，对不起
I gotta work. I'm sorry.
为什么不能请两天假？
Why can't you take a couple of days off?
我不行，我说过了
Because I can't. I told you.
这是我的婚礼
This is my wedding.
真的来不及了，走走走
Now we are late. Let's go,let's go!
好吧，回来再让你看录影带
Fine,you'll watch it on video when we get back.
菲比，你的书书，菲菲 谢谢
Here you go,Phoebe! Phoe-bo! Phoo-ba-la!
乖
You!
走吧，菲比再见 再见
Let's go!Bye,Pheebs!
伦敦，宝贝
London,baby!
天哪 你要抱抱吗？
Oh,God!Do you need a hug?
你不必拿东西给我
You don't have to bring me anything.
钱德，做点动作
Chandler,do something!
做动作啊 我有啊，我在不理你
-Do something! -I am. I'm ignoring you.
好吧，我来上镜头
I'll be the on-camera guy.
好，第一站，威斯敏斯特教堂
All right. First stop...Westminster Abbey.
那是什么？ 伦敦啊，宝贝
What is that?That's London,baby!
好，饭店在这里…等一下
All right,the hotel's here.Wait.
不对，我们要去…
We want to go
我知道了，我得进入地图里
I know.I'm gonna have to go into the map.
要是里面有个小钱德，杀了它
If you see a little version of me in there,kill it!
我知道了，走吧
I got it.Here we go!
我们不是要这样逛大街吧？
We're not gonna have to walk this way the entire time,are we?
你害我又乱了啦
Man,you made me lose it!
…那时候才10点
That was all before 10:00.
宴会打电话来说芦笋鸡换成基辅鸡
The caterer rang. It'll be Chicken Kiev,not Tarragon.
然后花匠说没有郁金香了
Then the florist said there are no tulips.
然后大提琴手得了 手腕隧道综合症…
And the cellist has carpal tunnel syndrome
艾蜜莉，亲爱的，好吗？
Emily,honey. Okay?
我也去你的
Well,up yours too!
什么？ 不是那个意思？
-What? -Oh,that's not what it means.
不，这是暂停的意思 对不起
-No! That's "time out." -Sorry.
放轻松，一切都会很美好
Sweetie,relax. Everything will be great,okay?
走吧
Come on,come on.
基辅鸡？
Chicken Kiev?
临时能有这道菜不错吧？
Doesn't that sound delicious at the last minute?
是啊，但鲑鱼会比鸡肉高雅
Salmon would be more elegant than chicken.
也不必担心沙门氏菌 （沙门音同鲑鱼）
And you wouldn't worry about the salmonella.
不过鲑鱼也可能有“鸡门氏菌”
But of course...with salmon you would have to worry about the chicknella.
真想赶快看到婚礼场地
I can't wait to see where you're getting married.
是的，那里很美 她父母就在那里结婚
It's beautiful. Her parents got married here.
它居然要被拆了
I can't believe they're tearing it down.
你绝对没看过那么美的房子 就在…
It's really the most lovely building. It's over
天哪
Oh,my God!
还不错
It's nice.
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
怎么会这样？怎么办？
What are we going to do?
放心，不会有问题的
Everything's gonna be all right.
怎么会没问题？ 说得也是
How's it gonna be all right?I see that.
我跟一个人问到了
I talked to a guy,and I found out what happened.
怎么回事？ 提前进行拆除
They tore it down early.
漂亮，威斯敏斯特教堂
All right!Westminster Abbey.
绝对是我见过最美的教堂
Hands down,best abbey I ever seen.
你觉得威斯敏斯特教堂如何？
What do you think of the Abbey?
很宏伟，他们正打算改名
It's great! They're thinking of changing the name.
改成什么？ 改成“摄影机收起来”
-To what? -To "Put the Camera Away"!
你真是威斯敏斯特坏脾气
Man,you are Westminster Crabby.
放心，你们会找到场地的
Don't worry,you'll find some place to get married.
抱歉，幸好红色沾血看不出来
Sorry. Lucky this dress is red.
不可能找得到场地 婚结不成了
We can't find another place.Then we can't have the wedding.
我订了一百五十人份的鸡肉 沙拉和蛋糕
I've ordered chicken,and salad,and cake for a 150.
一生中最快乐的日子 变成被食物淹死的星期天
What should be the most wonderfull day of my life...is rapidly turning into just Sunday with a spectacular amount of food.
你们会找到场地的
You're gonna find a place.
就算找不到，那就延期嘛 有那么糟糕吗？
But even if,God forbid,you didn't,so you postpone the wedding.Is that really so bad?
你想想，你可以筹备得很完整
Think about it. You could take all the time your needed to get everything that you want.
你可以订到郁金香…和鲑鱼
You could have tulips. You could have salmon.
鲑鱼喔
Salmon.
延期确实死不了
I suppose it wouldn't be the end of the world.
谢谢你
Oh,thank you.
总之你都会结婚，都会幸福 我妈都会比较喜欢你胜过喜欢我
Look,either way you're gonna get married. You're gonna be happy.My mom's gonna like you better than me.
天哪，她已经这么说了对吧？
Oh,God. She has told you that already,didn't she?
别起来，你需要什么？ 没什么
-Don't get up. What do you need? -Nothing.
我就是留下来照顾你的 你需要什么？
Come on. I'm here to take care of you.
屁屁夹到内裤了
Okay,I have a wedgie.
你自己解决
That is all you.
你中午想吃什么？ 我不知道
What do you want for lunch?I don't know.
我们是得吃饭 我一定要吃
I guess we have to eat.Yeah,I do.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
我应付罗斯的方式真差劲
I'm bummed the way I left things with Ross.
真后悔骗他说我要工作 他好像很气我
I wish I didn't lie about work. He seemed so mad at me.
别太苛责自己 要是我还爱的人要结婚…
Don't be so hard on yourself. If I was still in love with some
还爱？ 是啊
Still in love with?
我才没有爱着罗斯
I'm not in love with Ross.
是没有，很好，我也没有
Good!Yeah,me neither.
我不去是因为他是我的旧情人 去了会很不自在
I'm not at the wedding,because he's my ex-boyfriend...and that would be uncomfortable.
不是因为我还爱他 我跟大家一样喜欢罗斯
Not because I'm in love with him. I like Ross as much as anyone.
我对他的确有感情 但那不是爱
Clearly,I have feelings for him,but they don't mean love.
我对罗斯还有爱的感觉吗？有
I mean,do I still have loving feelings for Ross? Yeah!
我一直都有 但那并不表示我还爱着他
I have continuing feelings of love.But that doesn't mean I'm still in love with him.
我对他还有“性”趣 但我当然爱他
I have sexual feelings for him,but I do love him.
天哪
Oh,my God!
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
我们以为你知道 我们？
-We thought you knew! -We?
对，我们都知道，还经常在聊
We all know. We talk about it all the time.
你们都知道？罗斯知道吗？
You all know? Does Ross know?
不，罗斯什么都不知道
No! Ross doesn't know anything.
你们居然没告诉我
And you didn't tell me!
我们以为你知道，那么明显
We thought you knew. It's so obvious!
告诉你等于告诉莫妮卡 “喂，你很爱干净喔”
It would be like telling Monica:"Hey,you like things clean."
或是“乔伊，你是同志喔”
Or,you know,"Hey,Joey,you're gay."
什么？ 拜托，她老是拿着扫把
What?Oh,please,she's always got a broom in her hand.
想买什么？有围巾、明信片…
What are you in the market for? Scarves,souvenir postcards....
你看
Check this out!
这个就对了，你觉得呢？
That's the stuff! What do you think?
我不必买印着 “与笨蛋同行”的衣服了
I won't need that "I'm with stupid" T-shirt anymore.
我喜欢，钱给你
Well,I like it. Here you go.
你不是来真的吧 你丢我的脸丢得还不够吗？
You're not really buying that. Haven't you embarrassed me enough?
我丢你的脸？
Oh,I embarrass you?
我假装不认识你，无法回答
How can I answer when I'm pretending I don't know you?
他是在嫉妒，伦敦人都在戴
He's just jealous. All Londoners wear them.
是吗？那这里怎么没人戴？
Really? Then how come no one here anywhere is wearing one?
他们都是观光客
They're all tourists.
如果你要当街戴着那顶帽子 下午你就自己去逛
If you insist on wearing that in public...you're gonna spend the afternoon all by yourself.
如果要在你和帽子之间做选择 我选择帽子
If you make me choose between you and the hat,I choose the hat.
够英明 谢了
-Good choice. -Thanks.
够了，我要走了 我不想再丢脸了
That's it! I'm out of here. I won't be embarrassed any more.
你好，乔伊崔比亚尼，美国人
How are you doing? Joey Tribbiani,America.
我跟你爸谈过，你猜怎样？
I spoke to your dad,and you know what?
他觉得可以另外找到场地
He thinks we can find a new hall.
不必了 你找到地方了？
-We don't have to. -You found a place?
没有，但莫妮卡和我讨论过
No,but Monica and I were talking...
我为了礼堂被拆的事很烦 结果她建议把婚期延后
...and I was so upset about the hall being knocked down...and she suggested we put the wedding off for a bit.
她说什么？
She said what?
如果我不喜欢临时找个地方 我们就应该延期
If I won't be happy with somewhere we'd find in a day...we should postpone it.
延期
Postpone it.
你觉得莫妮卡知道 我们爸妈花了多少钱吗？
Do you think Monica realizes how much our parents spent on this?
你觉得我妹的小脑袋能理解
Do you think my sister's teeny,tiny,little brain comprehends...
大家特地挪出时间 大老远飞来这里吗？
...that people took time out of their lives...to fly thousands of miles to be here?
这么做是不对的
This isn't right.
我知道大家会失望 但他们下次一定会再来
I realize that people are gonna be disappointed.But I'm sure they'll come back.
我不能叫人家这么做，你会吗
I can't ask people to do that. Would you?
别拿你的裤子指着我
Don't you point your pants at me!
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
像样一点的场地一定没空档 你不懂吗？这是我们的婚礼
Anywhere half-decent will have been booked.Don't you understand? This is our wedding!
我只知道延期是不可能的 要结就现在结
Postponing it is not an option. This is when we're getting married.
意思是否则就不结？ 不，我是说现在就结
-You're saying it's now or never? -I'm saying it's now.
否则呢？ 我没说否则
-Or? -There's no "or" in mine!
这条裤子是怎么搞的？
What is wrong with these pants?
不是裤子，是你本末倒置
It's not the pants. It's you who's backwards.
要是你不懂这件事对我多重要 或许我们根本不该结婚
If you don't understand how important this is to me...perhaps we shouldn't marry at all!
艾蜜莉，等一下，别走
Emily,no! Wait,stop! Emily,please
买完东西有舒服一点吗？
Did shopping help you feel any better?
曼哈顿的店不够
Manhattan doesn't have enough stores.
我可以帮你忘了他 真的？
I can help you get over him.
对，拿一张罗斯的照片 一小片巧克力和一杯温水来
You can?I need you to bring me photos of Ross...and a small piece of chocolate...and a glass of tepid water.
是不是要跟墓地的土装在一起 挂在面北的树上？
Is this where you throw stuff in a bag with graveyard dirt and hang it from a north-facing tree?
要是你也在打嗝的话
Only if you have the hiccups too.
照片是给你的，其他是我要的 我只是不想起来
The chocolate and water are for me. I didn't feel like getting up.
我给你看一张罗斯的照片
I'll show you a picture of Ross.
你要去想他不好的地方
And you remember all the bad things about him.
专心想他的缺点 没问题，我们交往时我就这样
-Focus on his flaws. -I can do that.I did that while we were going out.
好，首先我想先声明 我爱罗斯，他真的好棒
Before we start,I want to say,for the record,I love Ross.He's such a great guy.
好，闭上眼睛 想像你跟罗斯在一起
Close your eyes.Imagine that you're with Ross.
想像你在亲他
Imagine that you're kissing him.
你的手在他的身上游移
You're running your hands all over his body.
你的手抚弄他的头发
You run your hands through his hair but
但是好恶！是某种发油
Gross! It's some kind of grease.
我不晓得 他的头发没那么困扰我
I don't know.His hair never bothered me that much.
那应该算是硬而不是油
It was more crunchy than it was greasy.
好吧，难度比我想的还高
This will be harder than I thought.
试试厌恶疗法好了
Let's try some aversion therapy.
看着照片 好
Look at the picture.
现在觉得怎样？
How do you feel now?
我比较不喜欢你了
Well,I like you less.
在英国玩也一样难玩
Well,It's just boring in England
抱歉
Sorry.
我才抱歉 我不该说你丢我的脸
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have said you were embarrassing me.
那样很过份
That wasn't cool.
如果你会高兴一点 我今天过得很悲惨
If it makes you feel any better,I've had a really lousy day.
我也是
Me too.
真的？ 才怪
-Yeah? -No!
我玩得超过瘾的
I had the best day ever!
你看
Dude,check this out!
有你的这段就快转，无聊死了
I'll fastforward your part because it's boring!
告诉我朋友你喜欢我的帽子
Tell my friend you like my hat.
好，你朋友叫什么？ 钱德（约克公爵夫人莎拉·弗格森）
-What's your friend's name? -Chandler.
钱德你好（约克公爵夫人莎拉·弗格森）
Hi,Chandler.
那不是… 那是弗姬，宝贝
-That's -That's Fergie,baby!
乔伊说你不喜欢他的帽子 但我觉得蛮时髦的
Joey says you don't like his hat,but I think it's kind of dashing.
听说你恢复单身了
So I hear you're single now.
我对帽子没喜欢到那个程度
- Yeah,I don't like the hat that much. -Okay.
你怎么会…什么时候…
When did you? How?
我想去白金汉宫
I was trying to get to Buckingham Palace.
就进入地图，然后…
So I'm in my map and
听说你和艾蜜莉谈过
I understand you had a talk with Emily.
没错，不客气
Yes,I did.And you are welcome.
是吗？ 是你提议把婚期延后的？
Am l?Was it your idea to postpone the wedding?
我要上厕所 等我
-I'm going to the bathroom. -Wait up!
既然你这么会解决问题 问题来了
Since you're the fix-it lady,here's a pickle:
当新娘说她不想结婚时 你怎么办？
What do you do when the bride says she doesn't want the wedding at all?
她这么说？ 对
She said that? Why?
为什么？ 我不知道
I don't know.
我说为了礼堂被拆就延期很蠢 她就捉狂了
I said it was stupid to put off the wedding......and she,like,flipped out.
天哪，你比我还笨
Oh,my God! You're even dumber than I am.
什么？
Excuse me?
你筹备这次婚礼多久了？
How long have you been planning this wedding?
不晓得，1个月吧
I don't know. A month?
艾蜜莉可能从5岁就在计划了
Emily's probably been planning it since she was 5.
从她第一次把枕头套 披在头上开始
Ever since the first time she hung a pillowcase from her head.
女生都这样
That's what we did.
我们梦想在一个完美的场地 办一场完美的婚礼
We dreamed about the perfect wedding.In the perfect place.
有一个完美的四层结婚蛋糕
With the perfect four-tiered wedding cake.
上面有小人偶
With the little people on top.
但最重要的是有个完美的男人
But the most important part...is that we had the perfect guy...
了解这一切对我们有多重要
...who understood just how important all that stuff was.
我都不知道
I had no idea.
我以为你披枕头套 是在学“快乐的修女”
That pillowcase thing,I thought you were doing The Flying Nun.
有时候是啦
Sometimes we were.
别哭了，帮我想想办法
Come on.Help me figure out what to do.
场面蛮紧张的 是啊
Pretty intense,huh?
希望罗斯不会以为 我们是怕尴尬才进厕所
I hope Ross didn't think we left because we were uncomfortable here.
希望他就是这么想的
I hope he did.
我想到一个缺点了 罗斯吃口香糖会吹泡泡
I thought of a good flaw. Ross pops his gum.
没错
Oh,right.
等等，我也会 是啊，那让我发疯
-Wait a minute. I do that too. -I know,it drives me crazy.
我来接
I'll get it.
菲比，我是乔伊
Pheebs,it's Joey.
乔伊
Hey,Joey!
我在地铁看到一个很像你的人
I saw someone that looks just like you on the subway.
我正想打招呼 又想到他不会在乎他长得像你
I was going to say hi,then I figured he doesn't care he looks like you.
你讲了我4块钱
That just cost me 4 bucks.
我打来问小鸡小鸭好不好
I called to see how the chick and the duck are doing.
它们跟菲比阿姨玩得很开心 瑞秋阿姨没什么用
They're having fun with Aunt Phoebe. Aunt Rachel hasn't been helpful.
你想我吗？
So do you miss me?
有点，但我玩得太高兴了
Kind of,but I've been having too much fun.
你还没想家？ 没有，应该没有
You're not homesick yet?I don't think so.
我们七个都很想你
Well,the seven of us miss you.
哪七个？ 我，瑞秋，鸡鸭，宝宝
-Who's seven? -Me,Rachel...the birds,the babies.
宝宝也想我？
The babies miss me?
当然想，不然就是我太饿了
Of course they do,or I'm just really hungry.
披萨来了 你们趁我不在叫披萨？
Pizza guy's here!You ordered pizza without me?
对，但我们有想着你 我们点了欢乐（乔伊）套餐
But we were thinking about you. We ordered the Joey Special.
两个披萨？
Two pizzas?
对，我得挂了，再聊
-Gotta go! Talk to you later. -Wait!
等等，你们叫哪一家的？
Where did you get it from?
（欢乐酒店）
他们永远欢迎您的光临
And they're always glad you came
要去就去一个 让你没烦恼的地方
You want to be where you can see Your troubles are all the same
要去就去一个 大家都认识你的地方
You want to be Where everybody knows your name
你带我来这里干什么？ 等着瞧
Why have you brought me here?You'll see.
我们不会结婚了
This wedding won't happen.
罗斯 好，但想像更多灯火
Ross.But imagine a lot more lights...
少一点砖瓦，还有鲜花蜡烛
...and fewer bricks...and flowers and candles
乐队可以摆在这里 椅子可以朝这边，然后…
And the musicians can go over here.The chairs can face this way and
你讲
You go.
不过要是你不喜欢 我们就改时间改地点
But if you don't love this,we'll do it any other place or time.
真的没关系，你高兴就好
Really,it's fine.Whatever you want.
这样很完美
It's perfect.
我不知道，要是下雨… 那就淋湿吧
And,I don't know,if it rains Then we'll get wet.
我连男朋友都没有
I don't even have a date.
菲比 怎样？
Phoebe？Ya？
你记得鸭子饲料在哪里吗？
Do you remember where the duck food is?
记得，在男生那边的水槽下面 怎么了？
In the guys' apartment,under the sink. Why?
因为我要去伦敦
Because I'm going to London.
什么？什么叫你要去伦敦？
What? What do you mean?
我得告诉罗斯我爱他
I have to tell Ross I love him.
保重，等我回来再生
Take care and don't have the babies till I get back.
那我们想了半天他的缺点呢？
But what about all the finding-his-flaws stuff we've been doing?
没用
Yeah,that didn't work.
你不能去，罗斯爱的是艾蜜莉
You can't go. Ross loves Emily.
我知道 但我得告诉他我的感觉
I know,but I have to tell him how I feel.
他应该知道所有状况 好做出知道状况的决定
He deserves all the information to make an informed decision.
才怪，你去是希望他说
You're going because you hope he'll say:
“我也爱你” “别理那个英国妹了”
"l love you too. Forget the British chippy."
你觉得他会吗？
You think he will?
不会，因为他爱那个英国妹
No,because he's in love with the British chippy!
你去了只会把他搞乱 毁了他的婚礼
You're just gonna mess with his head and ruin his wedding.
太迟了，你错过机会了
It's too late! You missed your chance.
抱歉，你一定很难受
I'm sorry. This must be hard.
但已经结束了
But it's over.
不，有人说“我愿意” 才算结束
No,it's not over until someone says,"l do."
我愿意！我愿意…
I do! I do!
谁追得上你，我怀了一窝猪仔
Like I can really chase you. I'm carrying a litter!
华森公馆
The Waltham residence.
是艾蜜莉的父母家吗？ 我是管家
Is this Emily's parents' house?This is the housekeeper speaking.
还有，小姐 讲电话不能这样讲
And,by the way,that is not how one addresses a person on the telephone.
先表明身份 再请你想找的人过来
First one identifies oneself...and then asks for the person with whom one wishes to speak.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
我们重来一次
Now,let us try that again,shall we?
不！天哪
No!Oh,my God!
华森公馆
-The Waltham residence. -Hello.
我是菲比布菲，我是想麻烦你
This is Phoebe Buffay. I was wondering,please...
如果不是很麻烦的话
...if it's not too much trouble,please...
我能和艾蜜莉华森小姐通话吗
...might I speak with Miss Emily Waltham,please?
华森小姐去排练餐会了
Miss Waltham is at the rehearsal dinner.
嘲弄别人的口音是不礼貌的 再见
And it is not polite to make fun of people. Goodbye.
不！我会有礼貌，我发誓 可以把现场的电话给我吗？
I'll be nice,I swear. Could you just give me the number for where they are?
我恐怕没有权利泄露这项讯息
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty to divulge that information.
有人正要去破坏婚礼 我得警告他们
Somebody is on their way to ruin the wedding,and I have to warn somebody.
你不给我号码，我就杀到伦敦 把你一脚踹到新咕噜肯夏去
So if you don't give me that number,I'm gonna come over there...and I'm gonna kick your snooty ass all the way to New Gloukenshire!
她知道我说到做到
She knew I could kick her ass.
乖儿子 妈
-Hi,sweetheart. -Mom,
爸
Dad.
抱歉迟到了 是我不好，我坚持要坐管子
Sorry we're late.My fault. I insisted on riding the tube.
茱蒂，孩子都在
Judy,the kids!
杰克，那是地铁的俗称
Jack,that's what they call the subway.
我以为… 爸，我们懂
-I thought -Dad,we got it.
我爸和继母来了
Here comes my dad and stepmom.
盖勒夫妇，这是史帝芬… 和安瑞亚华森
Mr. and Mrs. Geller.This is Steven... -Hello,darling....and Andrea Waltham
幸会
.Very nice to meet you.
亲爱的，是盖勒家的人 亲爱的，是亲家
Darling,the Gellers.Darling,it's the Gellers.
她只想着自己，我不该娶她的
She's very self-involved. I should never have married her.
你说什么？
What？
是盖勒家的人 在哪里？
-It's the Gellers. -Where?
那边一个，那边一个
That's one and that's another one.
很高兴认识你们 谢谢你们出一半的钱
Lovely to meet you.Nice of you to offer to pay for half the wedding.
不客气，去他的习俗 我们很乐意
The hell with tradition. We're happy to do it.
我们知道结个婚有多花钱
We know how expensive weddings can be.
而且以后可能就没机会了
Besides,this may be the only wedding we get to throw.
真是个世界通行的笑话
A joke that's funny in all countries.
您要吗？
Sir?
里面包什么？ 羊酪、水田芥和培根
-What's in it? -Goat cheese,watercress and pancetta.
这能吃吗？
That's not food.
这里的东西都不一样 我想回家
Everything's different here. I want to go home.
我想念我的家人，想念咖啡馆
I miss my family,the coffeehouse.
我连菲比的长相都不记得了
I can't even remember what Phoebe looks like!
我们才来3天
It's been three days.
你只是想家了 放轻松，好好玩就对了
Okay,you're just homesick.Would you just try to relax and just enjoy yourself?
连你都变了
You're different here too.
你在英国好坏
You're mean in England!
搞什么？ 怎么了？
What the hell?
我的这份帐单太疯狂了
What's up,Dad?This bill for my half of the wedding. It's insane.
怎么会这么贵？ 请客是在家里请
How can it be so much? The reception's at their house.
花，酒，一楼重铺地毯？
Flowers,liquor. Re-carpet first floor?
新的客用浴室，造景
New guest bath,landscaping.
我在出钱让他们装修
I'm paying to remodel this guy's house.
我要把那个混蛋骂一顿 爸，别激动
I'm gonna give that son of a bitch a piece of my mind.
我不想让艾蜜莉不开心 她这两天已经够心烦了
Please.I don't want anything to upset Emily tonight She's had a hard enough couple of days as it is.
给我，我去跟他谈
Here. Let me go talk to him.
告诉他谁也别想占盖勒家便宜
You tell him no one takes advantage of the Gellers.
杰克 有时候我都忘了你多有气概
Sometimes I forget how powerful you can be
我要去喝个烂醉
And I'm gonna go get drunk.
你好 你好
-Hello. -Hello.
下一班飞伦敦的班机？ 半小时后有一班
When is your next flight to London?There's one leaving in 30 minutes.
还剩一个空位 谢谢你
And I do have one seat left.
临时票的价钱是2700元
Thank you,thank you.The last-minute fare on this ticket is $2700.
卖我6百如何？ 抱歉
Huh. How about 600?
6百再加这对耳环
-Sorry. -How about 600 and these earrings?
公司是觉得最好不要
They prefer it if I don't barter.
我的信用卡额度不够
I don't think I have enough left on my credit card.
你可以分两张刷
You can split it with another card.
五张可以吗？
How about five?
谢谢
Thank you.
请出示护照
I'm just going to need to see your passport.
我没带，不过我可以告诉你 它就在我的床头柜上
I don't have it,but I can tell you exactly where it is on my nightstand.
这样吧，我有驾照 还有一张20元钞票
You know what? I have my driver's license.And I have a 20.
我爸不会付内建烤炉的钱
Face it. My father is not going to pay for the built-in barbecue.
还有，凉亭也免谈
And believe me,you can kiss your gazebo goodbye.
我或许可以争取到新草皮
I might be able to get you the new lawn.
那也得给草坪的装饰品
Then you have to give us the lawn ornaments.
我要是答应会被我爸笑死
I go back there with lawn ornaments,he'll laugh in my face.
太扯了，大家都说好了
This is ridiculous. I mean,we had an agreement.
史帝芬，你说句话好吗？
Will you say something,Steven?
别对我这么不客气
Don't take that tone with me.
好吧，随你
All right,you can.
菲比
Phoebe
谢天谢地，你改变心意了
Thank God!You changed your mind.
你现在或许想静一静 没关系，你这么做是对的
You probably want to be alone,you don't want to talk about it.You're doing the right thing.
再见 等等，你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
你又想干什么？等等
What are you doing? No,wait.
为什么每次她这样 我都在怀孕
Why am I always pregnant when she does that?
我想敬罗斯和艾蜜莉一杯
I'd like to make a toast to Ross and Emily.
我明天会正式敬酒 今天是非正式敬酒
My big toast is tomorrow.This is kind of my little toast,
也就是随便敬敬
or Melba toast,if you will.
好，我跟罗斯认识很久了 他第一次交女朋友我都知道
Okay.I've known Ross for a long time. I knew him when he was with his first girlfriend.
我以为他们很顺利 直到有一天他俩胀胎了
I thought things were going to work out for him,until the day he over-inflated her.
天哪
Oh,dear God!
华森府邸
Hello,Waltham lnteriors.
华森太太 我想找罗斯的伴郞之一或妹妹
Mrs. Waltham.I need to speak with one of the best men or Ross' sister,Monica.
你是谁？
-Who is this?
我是菲比布菲 罗斯最要好的朋友之一
-Phoebe,one of Ross' best friends.
你怎么知道这个号码？
How did you get this number?
跟你的女佣问的
I got it from your maid.
她很贱，但我比她更贱
She's a bitch,but I wore her down.
既然是罗斯的朋友怎么没来？
If you're one of Ross' best friends,why aren't you here?
我不能坐飞机 我怀了我弟的孩子
I can't fly. I'm having my brother's babies.
是广播节目吗？
Am I on the radio?
不是 我可以找他们吗？我有要紧事
Can I talk to one of them? It's important.
我对你没兴趣了，我要挂了
I'm bored of you now. I'm going to cut you off.
我也要踹她
Oh,okay,I'm going to have to kick her ass too.
很高兴罗斯和艾蜜莉 要在蒙哥马利礼堂结婚
We're excited that Ross and Emily are getting married at Montgomery Hall.
我朋友要在“蒙帝霍尔”结婚 （霍尔字同礼堂）
To think,my friend getting married in Monty Hall.
拜托，蒙帝霍尔啊 《大家来挑战》的主持人啊
Come on,Monty Hall!Let's Make a Deal.
笑一下吧
Come on,you people!
算了，恭喜
All right,forget it. Congratulations,Ross and Emily.
伴郞二号，乔伊崔比亚尼
Best man number two,Joey Tribbiani.
我没钱德那么会说笑话
I'm not good with the jokes like Chandler here.
我只想说恭喜这对幸福的新人
Congratulations to the happy couple.
我在我家附近咖啡馆认识罗斯
I first met Ross in this coffeehouse back home.
家
Home.
纽约市…在那里大家都认识我
New York City.Where everybody knows my name.
总之，我爱你们
Anyway...I love you guys.
但是我更爱美国
But not as much as I love America.
我们回家了好不好？
Can we please go home now?
你要回去了？ 我正想进一步了解你
Are you going home?I was hoping to get to know you better.
亲爱的，我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere,sweetheart.
我有笑啊
I was laughing.
有笑出声吗？
Out loud?
我不想让别人觉得我很白痴
I didn't want everyone to think I was stupid.
你好吗？
So how are you?
我妈快把我逼疯了
My mother's driving me crazy.
但我很替罗斯高兴 我不会让任何人扫我的兴
But Ross is getting married. I'm happy.I'm not going to let anything spoil that.
我只想说罗斯真是个好青年
I just want to say that Ross is a wonderful young man.
谢谢，我们都喜欢他
Thanks. We like him.
天哪，你生他时一定才十几岁
My God! You must have been a teenager when you had him.
我绝对不会付钱
There's no way in hell I'm paying for it.
好，我只问一件事
Look,we're down to just one point.
能不能婚礼后再解决？
Could we please just settle it after the wedding?
好，但我绝不付酒窖的钱 靠美国才没被德国殖民的小人
Fine,but I'm not paying for your wine cellar...you thieving,would-be-speaking- German-if-it-weren't-for-us,cheap little man!
那家伙醉了 你怎么可能像罗斯的妈
The guy was hammered. There's no way you look like Ross' mother.
那他为何会认错？ 因为他疯了
-Then why would he say it? -Because he's crazy!
之前他还谢谢我 在“泰坦尼克号”里演得很棒
He came up to me earlier and thanked me for my very moving performance in Titanic.
我妈说得对，我嫁不出去了
My mother's right. I'll never get married.
这么说就…
You know what,that is
谁不想要你？
Who wouldn't want you?
拜托 我是个儿子30岁的单亲妈妈
Please! I'm a single mom with a 30-year-old son.
我回来了，听着，我得…
-Hi,I'm back. Listen,I need to
你好
-Hello.
你好，我得赶11点那班飞机
Hello. I need to get on that 11:00 flight.
那架班机已经起飞了
I'm afraid that plane's already pulled away from the gate.
你得叫他们掉头回来接我
You're going to have to call that plane and tell them to swing around and pick me up.
我不能那么做
-Can't do that.
当然可以，就说引擎有问题
-Sure,you know what?We'll just tell them that there was,like,a problem with,like,the engine.
我恐怕得请你让开
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you to step aside,miss.
我不赶去伦敦，他会娶别人
Look,if I don't get to London he is gonna marry that other girl.
真不懂是为什么
Can't imagine why.
你知道吗？ 你不把那架飞机叫回来我就不走
All right. You know what?I am not leaving here until you call that plane back.
（暂停服务）
我今天要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
早啊，罗斯
Morning.
我今天要结婚了
-I'm getting married today! -Yeah,you are.
你觉得他有发现吗？
Do you think he knew I was here?
抱歉 是
-Excuse me. -Yeah.
要是你打算一路敲打到伦敦
If you're going to do that throughout the flight,tell me now...
现在就说，我好吃镇静剂
...so that I can take a sedative.
或是给你一颗
Or perhaps slip you one.
对不起，非常抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm very sorry. Sorry.
我只是有点兴奋
It's just,I'm kind of excited.
我要去伦敦告诉一个人我爱他
I'm going to London...to tell this guy that I love him.
我没跟你做过这档事
Well,I've never done that with you before.
是没有
No
你怎样？还好吗？
So how are you?You okay?
很好，你呢？
Yeah. Yeah. You?
很好…你呢？
Oh,yes. Yes.You?
我们问过了
We did you.
我该走了 好，当然
-I better get going. -Absolutely.
你能不能不要看？ 我不想看
Could you not look?I don't want to look.
你死哪去了？
Where the hell have you been?
我没回来睡 我认识了可爱的伴娘，她好…
I spent the night out. I met this cute bridesmaid. She is so
我不想听
I don't want to hear it!
菲比，我最喜欢的还是你
Pheebs,you know you're still my number-one girl.
不，出事了，瑞秋跑去伦敦了
No. No. We have an emergency. Rachel's coming to London.
太好了
Great!
一点也不好 她要去告诉罗斯她爱他
No,it's not great. She's coming to tell Ross that she loves him.
但是罗斯爱艾蜜莉 我知道
But he loves Emily.I know that!
你得阻止她，她会破坏婚礼 好
You have to stop her. She's going to ruin the wedding.Okay.
所以… 等等
-All right,so -Hold on,hold on.
瑞秋来了
Rachel coming.
想…办法
Do...something.
我该做的都做了 现在该你负责
I've done my part,okay?It's your responsibility now.
我卸下这个责任了，对吧？ 对
-The burden is off me.Right? -Right.
说说这个伴娘吧
So tell me about this girl.
结果我发现我的一切举动
And so then I realized,all the stuff that I had been doing...
向约书亚求婚、骗说我要忙
...proposing to Joshua,lying to Ross about why I couldn't come to the wedding...
都只是一种…
-...was all just a way -Oh,oh,oh,oh!
抱歉，可以打个岔吗？
I'm sorry,can I interrupt?
你真是个很糟糕，很糟糕的人
I just want to say that you are a horrible,horrible person.
你说什么？
Pardon me?
你说你爱这个人 却要去破坏他的大喜之日
You say you love this man,and yet you're about to ruin the happiest day of his life.
我不得不同意你朋友菲比的话
I'm afraid I have to agree with your friend Pheebs.
这是个很差劲，很差劲的打算
This is a terrible,terrible plan.
但他必须知道我的感受 为什么？
-But he has to know how I feel. -But why?
他爱这个艾蜜莉 这么做绝对没好处
He loves this Emily person. No good can come of this.
我觉得你错了 才怪
-Well,I think you're wrong. -Oh,no.
他并非真的爱她 只是失去我需要寄托
Well,he doesn't really love her. It's just a rebound thing from me.
你等着瞧 幸好我看不到
-You'll see. -Fortunately I won't.
还有，你们当时显然是分手了
And by the way,it seems to be perfectly clear that you were on a break.
想办法
Do something.
办法
Something.
你有看见莫妮卡吗？ 我不会见莫妮卡
-Have you seen Monica? -I'm not seeing Monica!
什么？ 什么？
-What? -What?
我们得找到她 菲比说瑞秋要来向罗斯表白
We gotta find her. Rachel's coming to tell Ross she loves him.
天哪
-Oh,my God!
没错，所以要找到莫妮卡 你知道她在哪里吗？
-I know. Do you know where Monica is?
不知道！你在逼问什么？ 干脆拿灯照我的眼睛算了
No. What's with the third degree? Why not just shine a light in my eyes?
我的天哪，跟仙境一样
Oh,my God!It's like a fairyland.
是啊，很恐怖吧？
I know. It's horrible,isn't it?
我好喜欢 希望我的婚礼也能这么美
I love it. I only hope my wedding looks this good.
我觉得… 有些话就别接了
-I just hope -You can let some of them go by.
开始注意瑞秋
Start looking out for Rachel.
我守前门 你守后面那个大洞
I'll cover the front door. You watch that big hole.
罗斯那里有钱德顾着
And I got Chandler covering Ross.
我干嘛管钱德在哪里？
Why would I care where Chandler is?
有的时候我根本不喜欢钱德
You know...sometimes I don't even like Chandler.
好
Okay.
我愿意…我愿意…我愿意
I do.I do.I do.
没错，第二个比较好 是吗？
-You're right. It's the second one. -Right?
乔伊 费丽西蒂
Hello,Joey.Hey,Felicity.
我整天都在想你 是吗？
I thought about you all day.
再跟我讲讲纽约的事
Talk New York to me again.
别管纽约了
Forget about it.
你好吗？
How you doing?
没什么好谈的 我们不会付酒窖的钱
There's nothing to discuss. We're not paying for your wine cellar.
你们总得折衷一下
You have to meet me in the middle here.
你再罗唆我就踹你的屁眼
My foot's gonna meet the middle of your ass.
怎么了？ 没事，一切都在掌握中
-What's going on? -Everything's under control.
你想干架？你是这个意思吗？
You want a piece of me,sir? Is that what you're saying?
够了，双方家长，退后
That's it! Parents! Parents! Back away!
这是我们的大喜之日
This is our wedding day!
你们给我好好相处 谁再多说一个字
From now on,everyone gets along.And if I hear one more word...
就别想抱孙子，没错
...no grandchildren! That's right!
知道了 抱歉
-Okay,okay. -Sorry,old boy.
我用大拇指就能扳倒你
I could kill you with my thumb,you know.
这是怎么回事？
What was all that about?
只是一些费用上的…
It was this disagreement over
天哪，你真美
My God! You look beautiful.
行礼前看到新娘会不吉利
You're not meant to see me before the wedding. It's bad luck.
我们的恶运应该都用完了
I think we've had all the bad luck we're going to have.
天哪，瑞秋
My God,Rachel!
你来了，我真不敢相信
You're here. I can't believe it.
你怎么跑来了？
What happened? Why are you here?
我只是来…
I just came to
我只是得告诉你…
I just needed to tell you...
恭喜你
...congratulations.
华森府邸
Hello,Waltham lnteriors.
华森太太吗？又是我，菲比
Mrs. Waltham? It's Phoebe.
为什么又是你？
Why?
我可以跟伴郞之一说话吗？ 我保证这是最后一次
Can I talk to one of the best men? This is going to be the last time.
有个女生找你
There's a girl on the phone for you.
真好
Great!
乔伊，是菲比 你有堵到瑞秋吗？
It's Phoebe.Did you stop Rachel?
没有，但没事 她只有抱抱他而已
No,but it's okay. She just came in and gave him a hug. That's it.
没有破坏什么？ 没有
-Nothing got ruined? -No.
太好了
That's so great!
现在怎么样了？
So,what's going on now?
我正在走红毯
I'm walking down the aisle.
还在走
Still walking.
我正要经过昨晚那个伴娘面前
I'm about to pass the bridesmaid I hooked up with last night.
我刚跟她说嗨
I just told her "hey."
我跟罗斯站在一起了 是菲比
I'm at the front with Ross.It's Phoebe!
他看起来很不爽
He looks pretty mad.
我得挂了 等一下！拿着让我听
I better go.Wait! Hold it up so I can listen.
昨晚的事真是… 愚蠢
-What we did last night was -Stupid.
既疯狂又愚蠢
Totally crazy,stupid.
我们在想什么？
What were we thinking?
我晚上去找你，好吗？
I'm coming over tonight though,right?
当然好
Definitely.
各位亲朋好友
Friends,family...
我们今天齐聚一堂 庆祝罗斯与艾蜜莉缔结良缘
...we are gathered to celebrate...the joyous union of Ross and Emily
愿今朝的幸福永远与他们同在 艾蜜莉，跟着我念
May the happiness of today...be with them always.Now,Emily,repeat after me.
我，艾蜜莉…
-l,Emily...
嫁给你，罗斯…
-...take thee,Ross....
做我合法的丈夫 祸福与共，至死方休
...as my lawfully wedded husband,in sickness and in health...till death parts us.
罗斯，跟着我念
Now,Ross.Repeat after me.
我，罗斯…
I,Ross...
迎娶你，艾蜜莉…
...take thee,Emily...
迎娶你，瑞秋…
...take thee,Rachel
艾蜜莉
Emily.
还要继续吗？
Shall I go on?
第一次…
"Mother,Mother,Pizza,Pizza," take one.
乐队准备好了？
Oh,the band's ready?
乐队怎么说我就怎么做
We gotta do what the band says,right?
我才懒得管乐队呢
I don't care about the stupid band!
太晚了。对走吧
-Well,it's getting late. -Here we go.
你们可以陪我一下吗？
Actually,you guys mind staying here with me for a while?
我们早上要赶（有“抓住”的含义）飞机
You know,we gotta get up early and catch the plane to New York.
对，那架飞机很大
Yeah,it's a very large plane.
怎么了？
Why,what's the matter?